If you've been searching for a stunning
luxury home in one of central Texas's
most charming small towns built by one
of the area's most premier luxury
builders, you're going to love this.
Today we're exploring Sten Mills in So,
Texas. This is a brand new construction
community offering thoughtful design,
small town charm, and homes starting in
the low 700,000.
Hi, I'm Andrea Dudik, local real estate
broker, and this is Living in Central
Texas, where we offer home tours,
community tours, and insights into all
things living in the Central Texas area.
So whether you're relocating or just
looking for your next place to call
home, you'll definitely want to take a
closer look at Stinit Mills in Cedo,
Texas. Stinit Mill sits in the heart of
Celo, Texas, just minutes off of I35.
giving you quick access to Austin,
Georgetown, Belton, and Temple. And it's
ideal for anyone who wants the peaceful
community feel while staying close to
major employers, hospitals, and
shopping. And of course, you're only
about 20 minutes out from Fort Hood and
about 35 to 40 minutes south of Waco,
Texas.
Here is me driving south on I35 from
Temple Belin. And Seleno was just 10 to
15 minutes away from South Temple. And
the drive is typically super easy with
minimal traffic.
Pulling into the community is super
quaint and you can see the charm of this
community and the ones surrounding it.
And what I love about this location is
that you're only about 5 minutes from
downtown Celo, one of Central Texas's
most unique and walkable destinations. a
picture boutique shopping, art
galleries, incredible food and drinks at
Barrow Brewing Company. The shed is
really popular along with Johnny's
Barbecue, and of course, the best little
taco truck, Moss Chugon Mexican Girl.
Stant Mill is developed by one of our
area's most respected luxury builders
known for timeless design, energy
efficiency, and top tier craftsmanship.
There are nearly a dozen floor plans
ranging from about 2600 to just 3500
square ft here. Offering all four
bedrooms, but 2 and 1 half to three
baths, and a variety of plans with
formal dining, office spaces, flex
rooms, and of course, threecar garages.
These homes feature open concept living
spaces, tall ceiling, designer lights,
and kitchens that truly make a
statement.
You have quartz countertops, custom
cabinetry, the finest finishes, and
oversized islands. All floor plans also
include covered patios, spacious primary
bedrooms, and on suite with luxury
finishes.
The level of detail you see here is what
sets this builder apart. I absolutely
love them.
So, it's super windy outside today, but
I really wanted to give you an outside
view of this home. Um, as you can see,
this community is really beautiful. All
of these homes are on halfacre lots. And
they have mature oak trees. That's also
a rare find in the area. This home is
like I would say 90% complete, maybe
even a little bit more. They're in the
finishing stages. It's probably about a
month out. Um, but they really just have
to put in the it looks like irrigation
and landscaping is what they're
finishing up and then they'll go ahead
and do some final details on the inside.
But I've always been really impressed by
this builder. They are a luxury builder
in the area. They build to a super high
standard. Um, you'll hear me say often a
lot of the things that they put into
their home standard are actually an
upgrade for a lot of other builders. So,
you're really getting that additional
price per square foot um with this
builder. Come on in. All of these lots
are on half acre plus lots. This is a
luxury price point. Um So, Texas is
going to be a slightly higher price
point than Temple and Belton in general.
Um I think it's kind of called like the
new Fredericksburg of the area if you're
familiar with Fredericksburg. But it's
a, you know, golf course community.
People driving around on their golf
carts. Very familyfriendly and just
welcoming. Super cute and charming town.
But this is uh the builder's Reagan
floor plan. It's a 4 bed, 2 and 1/2
bath, just under 2700 square ft. Plus,
you have a office space or flex space.
And then on this side, you have a formal
dining space. They're really staying
with the trends, which I love. They've
um, you know, are putting in really
tasteful light fixtures. We're missing a
bunch of bulbs in here. We try to put
them in for you, but they will give you
bulbs if you buy this house, I promise.
But just super elegant and upgraded
finishes. You have a floor to ceiling um
brick fireplace.
That one's going to be electric. Love
the wood beams running through the
center of here.
I always love they really do really
pretty windows. There's usually lots of
great natural lighting, but this is a
super open concept floor plan. Uh we
have your main living space here and a
in addition to your formal dining, you
have like a little eating kitchen and
then of course the most beautiful
kitchen. I love the colors and
selections they're making here. And just
remember if you don't love the finishes
in this home, they have about a dozen
other floor plans to pick from and we
can get you all those different finishes
and selections that they have in those
homes. In this home, they did. You're
always going to have beautiful custom
cabinets.
They did the two-toned cabinets in this
home. So, we have this really pretty, I
would say, kind of nearly honey oak
colored. Yeah. And then a green sagish,
what you say? Green forest. Sage color
on the
um island.
Just looks super pretty. I did not
intentionally match with this video
today, but it worked. They did that the
the brass uh the gold hardware, which I
think looks really polished. Again, I
love all the fixtures in in our areas.
Typically in central Texas, you'll often
find electric ranges. There are some
communities with natural gas. There
aren't a ton. And there are some
communities, especially in the higher
price points, with propane. This is an
electric one, but I'm from the West
Coast. That's something that a lot of
my, you know, West Coast will often ask
is, is their gas? It's not. If that's a
priority, too, definitely let somebody
know. And then on this side, you have
your builtin microwave,
double oven. It's a really great kitchen
for cooking and entertaining. Um, really
beautiful quartz countertops. I like
that there's this gold vein kind of
running through it that ties in to the
wood cabinets and light fixtures. This
is probably one of my favorite homes in
in terms of their design selection. They
have a whole design team dedicated to
staying trendy.
Average size pantry on this guy. Oh,
sorry. I'll stop you. All of our stuff
in there. Mhm.
for a lot for a lot of their homes,
they'll often do ceramic tile that looks
like wood, but in this one, they did the
big square tiles.
Um, you also have your built-in floor
plaids, which are convenient.
This is a split floor plan. So, when we
walk in, we have that beautiful foyer
with the dining and formal dining and
office opening up into this really
pretty living space, but then you your
very split floor plan for um your rooms.
So, the you're going to have carpets in
all of the secondary rooms.
You have this half bath right off of the
entry.
And then on this side
you have your primary suite. I don't
have the dimensions on this, but it's
pretty good size. I would guess
somewhere
16 by 12, maybe 15. You have a patio
entrance off of your primary suite.
And then they always do awesome kitchens
and awesome bathrooms. So there's a ton
of cabinet space in here. Very spaesque
bathrooms. Never seen them use this tile
before, but I think it's really fun
selections with kind of the uh warmer
tones they're going for. More of these
tan cream colors.
You have a nice soaking tub, a huge
walk-in shower.
This is your commode. You know what
those look like. Then you have dual
vanities. Again, so much space.
And they are notorious for just
fantastic closets.
We call we call this or I call this a
seasonal closet to where it's so high
you basically need a ladder to reach the
top shelves. So you could, you know,
rotate your seasonal winter clothes and
summer clothes, I guess, if you wanted
to. But this closet is massive.
Okay, so let's head on over to the other
side. Again, 2700 square ft. On that
side, you're going to have your patio
entrance to your backyard and your
threecar garage. And then you'll have
your
laundry room here with your washerd
dryer hookups,
additional
cabinet space, and a utility sink, which
is always super handy. And then on this
side, we have your three guest bedrooms
and your secondary
bathroom.
I really like the dual vanities in the
guest bathroom. That's not always a
thing either, but again, carpet in all
of these rooms. This one's a little bit
taller. They did off-white for the
walls, which I feel is trending back.
Gray was so popular for so long. I think
it is still popular, but definitely the
whites and um the whites are kind of
coming back, the crisper colors on the
wall.
So again, some things that are included
standard with this builder, not always
with others, that I think kind of put
them into that luxury line are going to
be the fixtures that they put into the
homes, the upgraded kitchens, usually
that 3 cm, that 3 cm quartz, a lot of
crown molding and accents,
fixtures, um, and sorry, hardware on
cabinets. That's not always a standard.
This one does have a security system.
They do a lot of outdoor kitchen. So, if
you love being outside or entertaining,
definitely a perk. Uh especially here in
Texas, you're going to have your
outdoor kitchen with a utility sink. Um
I'm not sure if they're going to be
including a grill on this one
or a fridge. You'll probably have to put
in your own fridge, but beautiful
halfacre lots. Plus, some of them are
larger than that. As you can see, the
grass isn't in yet, but it will have
full grass and irrigation. Again, not
all builders include full saw and
irrigation. So, another reason to have a
realtor help you through all of that
because we know what we're looking for.
We know what questions to ask and not
everything is included, although we'd
like it to be. And then you have this
really beautiful wood burning
outdoor fireplace.
So, I love the extended patio on this
one. The lot size, you know, you can
always put in a pool down the road, but
lots of uh vision and opportunity in
these homes pull.
And then lastly, we'll go ahead and
check out the garage. So, this is your
threecar garage. You do have the motors
for both. You have a water softener loop
setup.
This home is a corner lot.
You can see the one across the street is
also on a corner lot with its full sawed
in and just how big of a difference
the greenery
really is. I think one of my favorite
things about this community really is
all of those mature oak trees. Again,
you're not typically going to find a
brand new construction home with mature
trees like that. I think it's really
great.
One question I frequently get asked is,
"Do I really need a realtor when
purchasing new construction?" And the
answer is always yes. Even when working
with a builder, you definitely want a
realtor representing your best interest
and not the builders. As your realtor, I
help you navigate contracts, understand
incentives, negotiate upgrades, and
ensure you're protected through the
entire process. From your first
walkthrough to your final inspection,
builders love when buyers come in
prepared, and having an agent on your
side costs you nothing. The builder
typically compensates the agent. What
makes so special is its lifestyle. It's
artsy, historic, and full of character.
You'll find local festivals, art walks,
and live music year round, plus a strong
sense of community that people fall in
love with. This is a golf course
community, and a lot of places you'll
see people just driving around on their
golf carts, which is so stinking cute.
Families are drawn here for the highly
rated Celo ISD schools, low property
taxes comparative to a lot of places in
central Texas, outdoor recreation like
Celo Creek, which is a hidden little
Texas gem, Mil Creek Golf Course, and
proximity to Lake Belton in Stillhouse
Hollow Lake. It's peaceful, welcoming,
and still close enough to everything
Central Texas has to offer.
So whether it's this community or any
other new construction neighborhood in
central Texas, I'd love to be your
experienced realtor helping you through
it. It can save you time, money, and
stress and ensure you get exactly what
you're paying for.
Okay, so we hop next door. They're still
doing some work here, but I wanted you
to just get another feel for a different
floor plan and totally different design
style in this home. So, this is, as you
can see, this is more um warm toned, a
lot more dark browns, kind of more of a
moody feel. Super pretty. This is their
Clinton floor plan. I actually modeled a
lot of my own home off of this home cuz
the design and overall aesthetic of it
is just so awesome. But let's take a
little peek.
Hey,
hey, hey.
So, that's a look at Stinet Mills in
Sedo, Texas. A stunning new construction
community by one of our area's most
luxury builders. If you're thinking
about buying new construction or
relocating to the central Texas area,
I'd love to help you through the
process. And don't forget to like,
subscribe, and click the bell
notification so that you can stay up to
date on all things real estate here in
the Central Texas area. Till next time.